Justin Ervin

Software Engineer / Manager

Personal Info

Phone

256-473-5751

E-mail

justinaervin@gmail.com

Website

https://justinaervin.github.io/

Development Skills

Python

SQL/TSQL

JavaScript

C#

.Net

HTML & CSS

Design & Visualization

Data Analytics

Node.Js

Swift

iOS & iPadOS

Strengths

Relationship Driven

Self-motivated

Critical Thinker

Encourager

Philomath

Dedicated software engineer and manager with 10+ years of full stack experience developing mission critical systems for a fast growing aerospace company. Focused on automating and optimizing business activities that eliminate bottlenecks while significantly increasing throughput and decreasing human errors. Strives on challenges, curve-ball projects, ensuring the follow through, and the prospect of a happy end user.

Experience

2015-05 - present

IT Manager/Lead Software Engineer

Aerospace Coatings International

- Lead Software Engineer responsible for developing mission critical systems in multi-code environments.
- Designed and implemented inventory exchange system that integrated with existing ERP that optimized a current business activity, resulting in \$1M+ investment in the program
- Automated and optimized legacy ERP business activities to reduce processing time by 65%, reduce human error, and provide robust reporting tools
- Designed and built modern scalable RESTful backend API infrastructure with Node.js that replaced aging backend system
- Principal designer and lead developer of a team that implemented a suite of iOS apps that optimized mission critical work flows
- Built form automation system that enhanced flexibility resulting in either reduction or elimination of physical paperwork while decreasing errors
- · Headed team tasked with modernizing front-end and back-end infrastructure
- Led DevOps including VM management locally (VMWare & Nutanix) and in the cloud (AWS)
- Established & executed plans for long term & day to day managerial operations.

2013-05 -2015-05

Software Engineer

Aerospace Coatings International

- Designed & developed paid time off management system that led to a 95% reduction physical paper usage
- Designed & developed chemical inventory and tracking system that fully meet regulatory requirements and provided robust reporting options
- Invented drag and drop visual job assignment tool that reduced job assignment time requirements by 40%
- Established automated processes for requesting information from customer that reduced human processing and customer wait time

2010-01 -

IT Internship - Web Developer/Technician

2013-05

Aerospace Coatings International

- · Designed & built IT asset inventory and assignment system
- · Spearheaded bug fix team that improved end user confidence
- Maintained server and network infrastructure to beat required 99.99% up-time
- Strengthened relationship with end users and IT with "Here when you need us" program

Education

2015-09 -2017-08

Master of Science in Data Science - Indiana University

• Courses in: Machine Learning, Distributed Computing, Cloud Computing, Information Visualization

2008-09 -2013-05

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems - Jacksonville State University

- Courses in: Software Engineering, Database, Programming, Operating Systems, Networking, Web Services
- Minor: Business Administration
- Omicron Delta Kappa, Upsilon Pi Epsilon